birdsontheblog.co.uk 2015-12-09

# Cookie and Privacy Policies ⋆ Birds on the Blog

**Birds on the Blog**

**COOKIE AND PRIVACY POLICIES**

This Policy applies between

“You” “Your”                    the User of this WebSite and

“Us” “We” “Our”              Sarah Arrow and the Site http://birdsontheblog.co.uk

This Policy applies to Our use of any and all Data collected by Us in relation to Your use of the Site.

**1\. Definitions and Interpretation**

In this Policy the following terms shall have the following meanings:

**“Data”** | means collectively all information that You submit Us via the Site.  This definition shall, where applicable, incorporate the definitions provided in the Data Protection Act 1998;  
---|---  
**“Cookie”** | means a small text file placed on Your computer by this Site when You visit certain parts of the Site and/or when You use certain features of the Site.  Details of the cookies used by this Site are set out in Clause 12;  
**“UK and EU Cookie Law”** | means the Privacy and Electronic Communications (EC Directive) Regulations 2003 as amended by the Privacy and Electronic Communications (EC Directive) (Amendment) Regulations 2011;  
  
**2\. Scope of this Policy**

This Policy applies only to Our actions and Users with respect to this Site.  It does not extend to any websites that can be accessed from this Site including, but not limited to, any links We may provide to social media websites.

**3\. Data Collected**

Without limitation, any of the following Data may be collected by this Site from time to time:

3.1          name;

3.2          date of birth;

3.3          gender;

3.4          contact information such as email addresses and telephone numbers;

3.5          demographic information such as post code, preferences and interests;

3.6          IP address (automatically collected);

3.7          web browser type and version (automatically collected);

3.8          operating system (automatically collected); and

3.9          a list of URLs starting with a referring Site, Your activity on this Site, and the Site You exit to (automatically collected);

**4\. Our Use of Data**

4.1          Any personal Data You submit will be retained by Us for 6 months.

4.2          Unless We are obliged or permitted by law to do so, and subject to Clause 5, Your Data will not be disclosed to third parties.  This does not includeour affiliates and / or other companies within Our group.

4.3          All personal Data is stored securely in accordance with the principles of the Data Protection Act 1998.  For more details on security see Clause 11 below.

4.4          Any or all of the above Data may be required by Us from time to time in order to provide You with the best possible service and experience when using the Site.  Specifically, Data may be used by Us for the following reasons:

4.4.1         internal record keeping;

4.4.2         improvement of Our products / services;

4.4.3         transmission by email of promotional materials that may be of interest to you;

4.4.4         contact for market research purposes which may be done using email, telephone, fax or mail.  Such information may be used to customise or update the Site.

**5\. Third Party Sites and Services**

5.1          We may, from time to time, employ the services of other parties for dealing with matters that may include, but are not limited to, payment processing, delivery of purchased items, search engine facilities, advertising and marketing.  The providers of such services have access to certain personal Data provided by Users of this Site.

5.2          Any Data used by such parties is used only to the extent required by them to perform the services that We request.  Any use for other purposes is strictly prohibited.  Furthermore, any Data that is processed by third parties will be processed within the terms of this Policy and in accordance with the Data Protection Act 1998.

**6\. Links to Other Websites**

This Site may, from time to time, provide links to other websites.  We have no control over such websites and is in no way responsible for the content thereof.  This Policy does not extend to Your use of such websites. You are advised to read the privacy policy or statement of other websites prior to using them.

**7\. Changes of Business Ownership and Control**

7.1          We may, from time to time, expand or reduce Our business and this may involve the sale and/or the transfer of control of all or part of Our business.  Data provided by You will, where it is relevant to any part of Our business so transferred, be transferred along with that part and the new owner or newly controlling party will, under the terms of this Policy, be permitted to use the Data for the purposes for which it was originally supplied to Us.

7.2          In the event that any Data submitted by You is to be transferred in such a manner, you will not be contacted in advance and informed of the changes.

**8\. Controlling Use of Your Data**

8.1          Wherever You are required to submit Data, You will be given options to restrict Our use of that Data.  This may include the following:

8.1.1         use of Data for direct marketing purposes; and

8.1.2         sharing Data with third parties.

**9\. Your Right to Withhold Information**

9.1          You may access certain areas of the Site without providing any Data at all.  However, to use all features and functions available on the Site You may be required to submit certain Data.

9.2          You may restrict Your internet browser’s use of Cookies.  For more information see Clause 12.

**10\. Accessing Your own Data**

You have the right to ask for a copy of any of Your personal Data held by Us (where such data is held) on payment of a small fee which will not exceed ?10.

**11\. Security**

11.1       Data security is of great importance to Us and to protect Your Data We have put in place suitable physical, electronic and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure Data collected via this Site.

**12\. Cookies**

12.1       This Site may place and access certain first party Cookies on Your computer.  First party cookies are those placed directly by Us via this Site and are used only by Us.  We use Cookies to improve Your experience of using the Site and to improve Our range of products and/or services.  We have carefully chosen these Cookies and have taken steps to ensure that Your privacy is protected and respected at all times.

12.2       All Cookies used by this Site are used in accordance with current UK and EU Cookie Law.

12.3       Certain features of the Site depend upon Cookies to function.  UK and EU Cookie Law deems these Cookies to be “strictly necessary”.  Your consent will not be sought to place these Cookies.  You may still block these cookies by changing Your internet browser’s settings as detailed below.

12.4       This Site uses analytics services provided by Google and others.  Site analytics refers to a set of tools used to collect and analyse usage statistics, enabling Us to better understand how users use the Site.  This, in turn, enables Us to improve the Site and the products and/or services offered through it.  You do not have to allow Us to use these Cookies, as detailed below, however whilst Our use of them does not pose any risk to Your privacy or Your safe use of the Site, it does enable Us to continually improve Our business.

12.5       The analytics services used by this Site use Cookies to gather the required information.  Certain of these Cookies may be placed immediately when You decide to visit the Site and it may not be possible to obtain Your prior consent.  You may remove these Cookies and prevent future use of them by following the steps set out below.

12.6       You can choose to enable or disable Cookies in Your internet browser.  Most internet browsers also enable You to choose whether You wish to disable all cookies or only third party cookies.  By default, most internet browsers accept Cookies but this can be changed.  For further details, please consult the help menu in Your internet browser.

12.7       You can choose to delete Cookies at any time however You may lose any information that enables You to access the Site more quickly and efficiently including, but not limited to, personalisation settings.

12.8       It is recommended that You ensure that Your internet browser is up-to-date and that You consult the help and guidance provided by the developer of Your internet browser if You are unsure about adjusting Your privacy settings.

**13\. Changes to this Policy**

We reserve the right to change this Policy as We may deem necessary from time to time or as may be required by law.  Any changes will be immediately posted on the Site and You are deemed to have accepted the terms of the Policy on Your first use of the Site following the alterations.
